翻譯：宋小文
媽的
Shit.
呆在那，哥們
Hang in there, man.
打起精神來，麥克奈利。這只是一場比賽
Lighten up, McNally. It's only a game.
嘿，哥們，信不信由你，你上首發了
Hey, man, believe it or not,abcyou made the starting line-up.
你沒瞎說？
No shit?
沒啊，安德魯斯出水痘了
Yeah, Andrews has the chicken pox.
你至少在兩場比賽裡表現都很好
You're good for two games, at least.
好吧，那很好
Well, that's great.
如果你不喜歡，為什麼要這麼做
If you don't like it, why do you do it?
棒球就是我的生命
Baseball's my life.
喬莫，喬莫！過來
Jomo. Jomo! Come here.
過來
Come here.
現在，聽著，喬莫。
Now, listen, Jomo.
我要你把這個帶給哈利，好不好？
I want you to take this to Harry, all right?
帶給哈利！快去！帶給哈利！把他帶給哈利！
Take it to Harry! Come on!abcTake it to Harry! Take it to Harry!
走啊！帶給哈利！
Go on! Take it to Harry!
把它帶給哈利！
Take it to Harry!
去啊！快去，喬莫！
Go on! Go on, Jomo!
喬莫！喬莫！
Jomo! Jomo!
快去！快去！
Come on! Come on!
下來！下來！
Get down! Get down!
好吧，走吧
All right, come on.
- 我還是覺得你該走
- 不，我不能不上班
- I still think you should go.
- No, I can't get off from work.
但是你是唯一一個知道那些統計數字的人，我什麼都記不住…
But you're the only one that knows all those statistics. I can't remember nothing.
我的大腦就是個篩子。你是怎麼知道所有事情的？
My brain's a sieve.How do you learn it all that stuff?
在政府的報告上。在圖書館裡。
It's in the government reports.It's in the library.
你覺得他們會真的聽我們麼？
You think they'll really listen to us?
好吧，如果他們不聽，就會有1500桶的放射性廢物……
Well, if they don't, there's going to be 1,500 barrels of radioactive waste...
就埋在離這幾英里的地方。
buried just a few miles from here...
你的孫子輩可能長出三個腦袋。
and you might have grandchildren with three heads.
現在，我先和你排練一下。
Now, look, I'm going to rehearse you.
一個從波因特阿里納（加州地名）來的代表團也會去
And there's a delegation from Point Arena going, too.
傑利·貝克。他靠自己就很好
Jerry Baker. He's very good on his feet.
喬也會去
And Joe will be there.
我得走了，不然就趕不上車了，好麼？
Look, I got to go. I'll miss my ride. Okay?
瑪莎，記得學習小組是週四在我家
Martha, remember the study group'sabcat my place on Thursday.
好的！
Okay!
怎麼樣？
How did it go?
他們想要我去塔拉哈西（佛羅里達州地名）和大堂
They wanted me to go to Tallahasseeabcand lobby.
我說服他們帶喬和保拉去
I talked them into sending Joe and Paula.
喬和保拉？
Joe and Paula?
沒問題。他們會很好的
It's okay. They'll be all right.
這些混蛋哪來的膽量，把這些東西（指放射性廢物）放在離人這麼近的地方
The nerve those assholes have,putting that shit near human beings.
走吧，我要餓死了。
Let's blow this pop stand. I'm starving.
我們有鞋，還有兩輛車來應對聯邦調查局
We got shoes, two cars, for feds.
媽媽，喬莫還在那
Mom, there's Jomo.
你們倆，脫了牛仔褲上床睡覺
You two, get out of your jeans and into bed.
她會怎麼樣？
What's gonna happen to her?
- 有人會帶她回家的
- 我們之前完全不需要丟下她的。
- Someone will take her home.
- We never had to leave her before.
對不起了，孩子
Sorry, kid.
- 他得把它留著。
- 我以為我告訴你上床睡覺去了
- He got to keep that.
- I thought I told you to get in to bed.
- 現在是早上啊
- 上床睡覺！
- It's morning.
- Get into bed!
我要去洗頭髮。
I'm going to wash my hair.
這是誰？
Who's this?
爸爸媽媽。你以為是誰？
Mom and Dad. Who do you think?
你開玩笑吧。
You're kidding.
「阿瑟和安妮·波普繼續逃脫追捕……
"Arthur and Annie Pope continue to elude capture...
儘管這對在宣佈對1971年的爆炸事件負責後
"despite sightings of the couple, who went underground...
轉入地下的夫妻
"after claiming responsibility for the 1971 bombing...
在馬薩諸塞大學的軍事研究所曾被發現……」
"of the University of Massachusetts military research lab. "
「逃脫」是什麼意思？
What does "elude" mean?
沒被抓到。
Not getting caught.
「該實驗室是為了發展……
"The laboratory is credited with the development of napalm...
在越戰中被大規模使用的凝固汽油彈」
"used extensively in the Vietnam War. "
他們為什麼要炸了它（實驗室）？
Why did they have to blow it up?
他們被禮貌地要求停止製造的時候，並沒有停止
They didn't stop making it when they asked them politely.
快點，丹尼！我是認真的！
Come on, Danny, I'm serious!
他們把那東西用在人身上。
They were dropping that stuff on people.
「安妮·波普是從前的安妮·帕特森……
"Annie Pope is the former Anne Patterson...
美國心靈傳動的主席唐納德·帕特森的女兒」
"daughter of Donald Patterson, president of American Telekinetics. "
這是外公？
Is this Grandpa?
- 肯定是。
- 那這是外婆？
- It must be.
- And Grandma?
對。
Yeah.
你記得他們麼？
Do you remember them?
- 不記得。
- 一點都不記得了？
- No.
- Not even a little?
他們看起來有點緊張
They look kind of uptight.
- 到處都是工業廢物。
- Industrial waste all around.
趁熱吃，趁新鮮
Get them while they're hot.Get them before they rot.
- 你媽媽呢？
- 她在洗澡
- Where's your mother?
- She's in the shower.
我今天早晨採訪了一些很瞭解波普一家的人
I talked this morning with some of the people who knew the Pope family best.
約翰·康格和這個在佛羅里達城
John Kungle played ball with the young man...
被稱為理查德·麥克奈利的年輕人打過球。
who was known here in Florida City as Richard McNally.
他是個好學生，也是個好朋友？
He was a good student, and a good friend?
他是個好哥們。
He was a cool dude.
故事就是這麼編出來的。
That's how legends are made.
他智商多高？49？
What's his IQ? 49?
- 他要去加州大學洛杉磯分校。
- 你沒開玩笑？
- He's going to UCLA.
- No kidding?
對，我沒開玩笑。我說了他要去加州大學洛杉磯分校
No, I'm not kidding.I said, he's going to UCLA.
對不起。
Excuse me.
這對夫妻的這些照片看起來20歲
These photos of the couple are 20 years old...
而且並不可靠
and are not considered too reliable.
這對夫妻因為1971年那場使一個看門人失明的
The couple is still wanted for the 1971 bombing of their university lab...
實驗室爆炸事件仍被通緝
in which a janitor was blinded.
邁阿密的美國聯邦調查局官員表示，儘管他們有兩個孩子……
FBl officials in Miami said that despite the presence of their two children...
……波普一家仍應被認為有武裝，很危險
the Popes should be considered as possibly armed and dangerous.
在接下來的本地新聞中……
In further local news...
給你帶了吃的
There's food for you.
你看起來真漂亮，媽媽
You look pretty, Mom.
上床睡覺，小朋友
Get into bed, Kimosabe.
好的，我們看看
Okay, let's see.
藍眼睛，金色頭髮。你可以了。
Blue eyes, blond hair. You're okay.
怎麼了？
Or are you?
怎麼了，孩子？
What's the matter, kid?
不知道
I don't know.
我就是覺得有點糟糕，你知道麼
I just feel kind of lousy, you know?
17歲的時候應該這麼覺得的。
You're supposed to feel that way at 17.
真的？
Really?
你照鏡子的時候都認不出你自己，這太棒了
It's terrific not recognizing yourself when you look in the mirror.
每六個月就換一個新名字，真棒啊
It's wonderful having a new name every six months.
我們呆在那很長時間了。很難離開。
We were there a long time.It's hard to leave.
我們可能還得給你剪剪頭髮
We may have to cut your hair, too.
沒準這次我還得剃光頭
Maybe this time I could shave my head.
- 把你弟弟帶進來。
- 好
- Send your brother in.
- Yeah.
我討厭這樣
I hate this.
費城人昨晚又贏了
The Phillies won again last night.
那麼看起來還不錯
Things are looking good, then.
好極了
Things are looking great.
麥克阿瑟和杜魯門有仇
The MacArthur feud with Truman.
我覺得本地的報紙沒有這個。
I don't think we covered that in the local paper.
也許你該試試《華盛頓人》
Maybe you better try The Washingtonian.
不，我是感興趣它對國家的中心地帶有什麼影響
No, I'm interested in how it affected the heartland of the nation...
那些小的社區。
the small communities.
- 這是社會史
- 我可以給你看《鷹報》
- This is social history.
- I could show you The Eagle.
我們只是把我們過去的話題放在微縮膠片裡
We just put our back issues on microfilm.
- 這就是？
- 把它拿到那。
- This is it?
- Take it right over there.
謝謝。
Thank you.
聖馬丁醫院，醫療記錄
St. Martin's Hospital, Medical Records.
- 三美元？
- 是。
- Three dollars?
- Yes.
你想把它寄到哪，曼斯菲爾德先生？
Where do you want it mailed, Mr. Mansfield?
曼菲爾德。
Manfield.
不用了，我自己拿
No, I'll pick it up.
我需要個護照，公司要派我去開羅
I need to get a passport.The company's sending me to Cairo.
- 你做石油？
- 軍事。
- Are you in oil?
- Military.
你現在聽到的是你最喜歡的老歌頻道，來自弗吉尼亞州的羅福（弗州地名）……
You're listening to your favorite oldies station in Norfolk, Virginia...
拉爾夫，你需要喂貓
Ralph, the cat needs to be fed.
還需要什麼別的嗎
Need anything else?
- 不用了。兩個星期內我會再打電話的。
- 好的。
- No. I'll call the booth again in two weeks.
- Okay.
聽著。你母親……
Listen, your mother...
她四周前去世了。癌症。
She died four weeks ago. Cancer.
你父親當時在她身邊。
Your father was with her.
你當時有麻煩，聯繫不上你
You were just too hot to contact.
他讓我告訴你不要擔心他，他很好
He said to tell you not to worry about him.He's okay.
我很遺憾。
Sorry.
好吧，誰要午飯？
Okay, who wants lunch?
我
Me.
金槍魚怎麼樣？
How's tuna?
好
Yecch.
我班裡有個人，要拿杜克·斯奈德（美國棒球球員）的卡和我換巴倫蘇埃拉（墨西哥棒球球員）的。
There's a kid in my class who traded me Duke Snider for Valenzuela.
嗯，所以呢？
Yeah, so?
所以他是個混蛋
So, he's a jerk.
斯奈德的卡值20美元
Snider's worth about $20.
他是布魯克林道奇隊的
He's from the Brooklyn Dodgers.
他老了
He's old.
這卡是個古董
This card is an antique.
- 我能要白麵包麼？
- 吃吧
- Can I have white bread?- Just eat it.
嘿，孩子
Hey, kid.
你。你叫什麼？
You. What's your name?
麥克
Michael.
- 你為什麼問他這個？
- 他還不習慣他的新名字。
- Why are you asking him that?
- He's not used to it yet.
他最好快一點習慣它
He better get used to it fast.
我叫什麼？
What's my name?
- 保羅
- 保羅什麼？
- Paul.
- Paul what?
- 保羅·曼菲爾德。
- 拼出來。
- Paul Manfield.
- Spell it.
M- A-N...
F- I-E-L-D.
- 你媽媽叫什麼？
- 別問了
- What's your mother's name?
- Just stop it.
我等你說。
I'm waiting.
辛西婭。
Cynthia.
你弟弟呢？
And your brother?
史蒂芬，行了吧？
Stephen, all right?
你他媽的出什麼毛病了？
What the hell's your problem?
我在市內找了些衣服。
I got some clothes in the city.
你可以穿二手店的這些。新的這些衣服……
You can wear the thrift shop ones.The new ones...
要先洗一洗
have to be washed first.
遵命，先生！
Yes, sir!
今天下午，對不起
Sorry about this afternoon.
我母親蘇菲去世了。
Sophie's dead.
什麼？
What?
一個月前。癌症。
A month ago. The big "C."
哦，寶貝
Oh, babe.
聯邦調查局來之後，我告訴她我們沒事
I talked to her after the feds came,to tell her we were okay.
她從來沒洩露我們的消息。
She never let on.
我都能看見她和莫裡斯站在那
I can just see her standing there with Morris.
兩個胖胖的老猶太人，前布共產黨……
Two fat old Jews, ex-Bolsheviks...
在洗衣房給他們紅尿布（指共產黨後代）的孩子打電話……
talking to their red-diaper baby on a phone from a Laundromat...
而她那時候已經快要去世……
and she's fucking dying.
那女人很愛我。
That lady loved me.
去年冬天，當他們安排我母親在芝加哥見我的時候
Last winter, when they arranged for her to meet me in Chicago...
她在收到通知的一個小時之內就飛了過來
she flew there on an hour's notice...
一個人，還下著暴風雪
alone, in a blizzard.
她很害怕坐飛機的
She's terrified of flying.
她下飛機的時候臉都綠了
She was green when she got off the plane.
我帶她到休息室聊天
I took her over to the lounge to talk...
我們坐在角落裡，我說「我希望事情容易一點」（I wish it was easier）
and we sat in a corner and I said,"I wish it was easier. "
她說「應該說『我希望事情容易一點（You wish it were easier）』」
"You wish it were easier," she says.
她竟然在糾正我的語法錯誤……
She's correcting my grammar...
就像我是她教的小孩子一樣
like I'm one of the kids she teaches.
現在已經沒有讓我們回去的動力了。
There's nothing left to go back to now.
只有我們和孩子們了There's only us and the boys.
只剩下我們了
We're all that's left.
我們必須……
We must...
我們必須依靠彼此
We have to hang on to each other.
我能看他的檔案嗎？
May I see his records?
抱歉，我弄丟了
I'm afraid I lost his records.
他們把檔案給我了，我也記得裝上了
They gave them to me,and I know I packed them...
可是我就是找不到了
but I just can't find them.
我一直丟東西，是不是？
I'm always losing things, right?
我丈夫說，要不是擰上了，我連頭都能丟
My husband says I'd probably lose my head if it weren't screwed on.
但是我可以重新做一份
But I can write for a copy.
記得做一份檔案，好嗎？
Make sure to write for those records,okay?
你可以選兩節選修課。
You can have two electives.
音樂，打字，機械，電腦編程，還是家政？
Music, typing, mechanics, computer programming, or home economics?
音樂。
Music.
- 還有呢？
- 還有……
- And?
- 家政吧。
- 他爸爸是廚師。
- Home economics.
- His dad's a cook.
找個空座位，曼菲爾德先生。
Find an empty seat, Mr. Manfield.
好的，聽著，各位
All right, listen up, everyone.
再聽一遍。
Listen again, please.
好的，現在有誰能告訴我這兩段音樂有什麼區別？
Now, can anyone tell me the difference between these two pieces?
你說？
Yes?
一個是流行，另一個是古典
One is pop and the other is classical.
至少我知道你不是聾子
At least we know you're not deaf.
你覺得呢，斯伯丁先生？
How about you, Mr. Spaulding?
能不能給我們區分的更深一點？
Could you give us a deeper distinction?
第一個很爛……
The first one's bad...
第二個很好。
and the second one's good.
這是個觀點，不是事實。
That's a matter of opinion, not a fact.
這屋子裡一定有好幾個人不同意你的看法
I'm sure there are several people in this room who would disagree with you.
你覺得呢，曼菲爾德先生？
How about you, Mr. Manfield?
敢不敢試著說一下？
Would you care to venture a guess?
你沒法跟著貝多芬的音樂跳舞
You can't dance to Beethoven.
很好，曼菲爾德先生。你聽很多貝多芬的音樂？
That's very good, Manfield.Do you listen to much Beethoven?
不，沒有。
No, not really.
那你怎麼聽出這段是貝多芬？
How did you identify this piece?
我猜我之前聽過這段吧。
I guess I've heard some.
我確定班裡的其他人也能聽出另一個作者
I'm sure the rest of the class can identify the other composer.
說的很對。沒法跟著貝多芬的音樂跳舞。
You're quite correct.abcYou can't dance to Mr. Beethoven.
能告訴我為什麼嗎，曼菲爾德先生？
Can you tell me why, Mr. Manfield?
因為貝多芬的這段……
Because the Beethoven piece...
沒有一個固定的節奏，或者說拍子
doesn't use a constant rhythm or tempo!
麥當娜的歌一直都是四四拍
Madonna is 4/4 time all the way through.
旋律會變，但是節奏一直不變
The melody changes,abcbut the rhythm is constant.
所以你就可以跟著它跳舞
So you can dance to it.
而四重奏，是旋律和節奏都會改變。
The quartet changesboth melodically and rhythmically.
我會再放一遍。聽著。
I'm going to play them again.Listen for this.
曼菲爾德先生
Mr. Manfield.
我們得給你找個樂器
We'll have to find an instrument for you.
樂器？
An instrument?
選音樂課的都要在樂團演奏。
Everybody who takes music is required to play in the orchestra.
你會什麼樂器嗎？
Do you play something?
鋼琴。
Piano.
彈一段。
Play something.
好的，你沒必要去樂團演奏了。
Well, there's one thing you don't have to do, and that's play in the orchestra.
我想聽聽你在我家的斯坦威鋼琴上彈的怎麼樣。
I'd like to hear how you sound on the Steinway I have at home.
出去吧
Get out of here.
- 找到工作了，爸爸？
- 找到了，就在城裡。
- Get a job, Dad?
- You betcha I did. Right in town.
- 我是廚師。猜是做什麼菜？
- 意大利菜？
- I'm a cook. Guess which kind?
- Italian?
- 猜對啦。
- 太棒了！
- You got it.
- Radical!
非得這麼說話麼
Do you have to say that?
- 從哪拿到這個的？
- 公共圖書館的失物招領處。
- Where'd you get this?
- Public library lost and found.
就在餐廳的轉角處
It's right around the corner from the restaurant.
這四月會很冷，我覺得你用得到
April can be cold up here.I thought you might needthese.
別讓你這雙拿球棒的手凍裂了。
Keep those slugger hands from cracking.
- 進球隊了麼？
- 嗯
- Did you make the team?
- Yeah.
- 太棒了
- 我有什麼？
- Great.
- What about me?
對不起，孩子。東西都沒有你的號。週末我去電影院試試
Sorry, kid. Nothing in your size. Have to try a movie theater on the weekend.
這提醒了我，週六得去砍些柴火
Which reminds me, we have to chop some firewood on Saturday.
哦，爸爸，我明天做這個。明天我不上學。
Oh, Dad, I'll do it tomorrow.I'm not going to school.
- 為什麼？
- 他們在拍班級合照
- How come?
- They're taking class pictures.
好。
Right.
- 那學校怎麼樣？
- 還不錯
- How is that school?
- Not bad.
- 老師知道點你不知道的東西？
- 嗯，他們還不錯。
- Teachers know anything you don't?
- Yeah, they're okay.
你註冊的時候遇到麻煩了嗎？
Did you have any trouble with the registration?
今天放學的時候我去見了輔導員。
I had to see the guidance counselor at the end of the day.
然後呢？
And?
他想知道我要申請哪個大學
He wanted to know what colleges I was applying to.
你告訴他什麼了？
What did you tell him?
呃，我說我還沒決定。
Well, I said I hadn't decided yet.
好。就和他們隨便說點什麼，然後忘了吧。
Good. Just tell them something, and forget about it.
不然他們會一直偷聽你。
Otherwise they'll keep bugging you.
- 你怎麼樣，小東西？
- 我不要胡椒
- How about you, small stuff?
- I don't want peppers.
上帝保佑
Bless you.
我們班有個人真的很瘋狂
There's a kid in my class who's really crazy.
你的精神又沒正常到哪去
You're not exactly the poster child for mental health.
他記得火車時刻表
He knows train schedules.
你從來不需要知道。你可以在手裡有一份，然後就都知道了。
You never know.It might have come in handy.
真的，爸爸。整個國家的他都知道。
Really, Dad. All over the country.
他知道火車什麼時候從奧馬哈到佐治亞州的亞特蘭大
He knows what time trains leave from Omaha to Atlanta, Georgia.
像這樣的東西
Stuff like that.
得認識認識這孩子。你拿著這別針幹什麼呢？
Get to know this kid.What are you doing with that safety pin?
什麼別針？
What safety pin?
- 我找到工作了。
- 真的？
- I got a job.
- Really?
告訴我們，親愛的。
Tell us, my dear.
你要怎麼奉獻這個虛假的資本主義經濟？
How are you going to contribute to this false, capitalist economy?
我要做一個米爾頓·克斯維爾醫生的接待員。
I'm going to be a receptionist for a Dr. Milton Cosswell.
- 是嗎？
- 對。
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
郵局有個招聘的告示
There was a sign up at the post office.
他不介意付我現金
He doesn't mind paying me in cash.
他甚至都沒問為什麼。
He didn't even ask why.
應該是對他避稅還是什麼的有好處吧。
It's probably good for his taxes, or something.
不管怎麼樣，有工作意味著如果我們需要，就可以拿點東西來用
Anyway, it means I can pick up supplies, if we need them.
他看起來是個好人
He seems like a pretty nice guy.
謝謝媽媽
Mom, thanks.
聽著不錯。看起來我們都得到想要的東西了
Sounds good. Looks like we all got what we wanted.
有人在家嗎？
Hello, is anyone home?
有人嗎？
Hello?
你是誰？
Who are you?
我是住這的。那你是誰？
I live here. Who are you?
- 菲利普斯先生是你父親？
- 是。
- Is Mr. Phillips your father?
- Yes.
穿粉色衣服的這是你……
And is this you in the pink-
哦，別想它了。
I've destroyed the negative.
現在你知道我是這的人了，該說說你了
So now we've determined that I belong here. Let's talk about you.
你父親說我可以彈他的鋼琴，而且門是開著的
Your father said I could use the piano. And the door was open.
- 我們有門鈴的
- 我按門鈴了
- We do have a bell.
- I rang the bell.
沒人應，我就進來了，對不起。
No one answered, so I came in. I'm sorry.
你在我父親的學校？
You go to the school?
是
Yeah.
- 我沒見過你。
- 那是因為我剛來
- I haven't seen you there.
- That's because I just started.
所以你今天怎麼沒去上學？
So how come you're not there?
我昨晚發燒了，我媽讓我呆在家裡
I had a fever last night.My mom made me stay home.
- 那你為什麼不呆在家裡？
- 我今天好多了，還很無聊
- Why didn't you?
- I felt better today. And I was bored.
你真奇怪。我今天翹課了。
You're strange. I cut.
我可不想和這些非人類一塊拍照。
I didn't feel like having my picture taken with those subhumans.
你很好，你知道
You're very good, you know.
我還可以
I'm okay.
你叫什麼？
What's your name?
- 麥克。
- 我叫羅娜
- Michael.
- I'm Lorna.
我還是走吧
I'd better be going.
- 你從哪來？
- 奧克蘭。
- Where are you from?
- Oakland.
- 你生在加州？
- 不，紐約
- You born in California?- No, New York.
真的？
Really?
我想去紐約上學，但我媽媽怕我被搶劫
I want to go to school in New York, but my mother's afraid I'll get mugged.
你家經常搬？
Your family move around a lot?
不，不是。你彈鋼琴麼？
No, not really. You play?
天哪，不。我可受不了練琴。
God, no. I couldn't stand to practice.
我哥哥是演奏家
My older brother is the virtuoso.
他上耶魯，他做什麼都對。你要去哪個大學？
He's at Yale. He does everything right.Where are you going?
哦，那個啊。我還沒怎麼想過。
Oh, that.I haven't thought about that much.
你還沒怎麼想過？下個學期可就要申請了。
You haven't though about it much? You're going to have to apply next semester.
是麼？
Yeah?
你什麼意思，「是麼」？
What do you mean, "Yeah?"
你看，我真的……真的得走了。
Look, I really... I gotta go.
你很有資格。
You're certifiable.
不用謝。
You're welcome.
曼菲爾德先生，我想和你說句話。
Mr. Manfield, I'd like a word with you.
我知道你昨天去了我家。
I understand you had occasion to visit my house yesterday.
我去看你的鋼琴了
I went to look at your piano.
我知道你不只是看看而已。
I understand you did more than look at it.
- 你家裡有鋼琴嗎？
- 沒有，先生
- Do you have a piano at home?
- No, sir.
那你怎麼練習？
How do you practice?
我不能常練。
I can't much.
你是個很有才華的音樂家，曼菲爾德……
You're a talented musician, Manfield...
但你沒有像罪犯一樣（進別人家）的權利。
but that doesn't give you theright to act like a criminal.
清楚了嗎？
Is that clear?
是的，先生。
Yes, sir.
曼菲爾德？
Manfield?
我們會給你找個鋼琴。
We'll find you a piano.
讓我看看，姑娘們。
Now let me see, girls.
謝謝，去隊尾吧。
Thank you. Just go to the back of the line.
你很有資格啊。
You are certifiable.
這是怎麼回事？開什麼玩笑？你上廚藝課？
What is this? Some sort of smart-ass joke? You're taking cooking?
我想學做菜。
I want to learn how to cook.
是啊，對。你有強烈的慾望想學怎麼做Apple Brown Betty（一種用蘋果和麵包屑製成的甜點）。
Yeah, right. You have a burning desire to learn how to make Apple Brown Betty.
你要是這麼想，那你在這幹什麼？
What are you doing here,if you think so highly of it?
他們不讓我學機械……
They wouldn't let me take auto mechanics...
我也沒時間把這事告到最高法院。
and I didn't have time to take the issue to the Supreme Court.
既然剩下了菲利普斯和曼菲爾德
Now that leaves Phillips and Manfield.
你們可以用最後一張台嗎？
Please, would you take the last booth?
今天的菜譜……
Today's menu...
是金槍魚核桃砂鍋
is tuna-walnut casserole.
這大概也算是機械吧
This may be auto mechanics after all.
拿著四杯量的量杯。
Take your four-cup measuring bowl.
你知道，我父親覺得你是切片麵包之外最好的東西
You know, my father thinks you're the best thing since sliced bread.
他可不是這麼對我說的
That's not what he told me.
一罐金槍魚
A can of tuna.
聽著，別擔心。別讓他嚇著你。
Listen, don't worry.Don't let him scare you.
如果他覺得你可以演奏，你就可以為所欲為了。
You can do anything if he thinks you can play music.
半杯核桃
Half a cup of walnuts.
週六有室內樂演奏會
We're having a chamber music concert Saturday.
無聊的要死，你還得穿的像去葬禮一樣……
And they're boring as hell, you have to dress for a funeral...
但是你應該會喜歡。想來嗎？
but you'd probably like it.abcYou want to come?
兩根芹菜
Two stalks of celery.
- 好，我考慮考慮。芹菜。
- 芹菜。
- Yeah, I've got to think about it. Celery.
- Celery.
在這。
Here.
他被那些資產階級的垃圾引誘了
He's getting seduced by all this bourgeois crap.
- 去他的室內樂
- 那是音樂啊，看在上帝的份上
- Fucking chamber music.
- It's music, for God's sake.
頹廢的，白皮膚的，特權階級的垃圾
Decadent, white-skinned, privileged crap.
一大堆人打著領帶穿著連褲襪坐著扶手椅，呆在一塊
Lot of people sitting around in ties and pantyhose in wing chairs...
- 像在你母親家
- 像在我母親家。
- like at your mother's house.
- Like at my mother's house.
他不能去。
He's not going.
- 誰說的？
- 我說的！
- Says who?
- Says me!
- 我不信。
- 看我的口型：他不能去！
- I don't believe you.
- Read my lips: He's not going.
你什麼時候成了文化部長？
Since when did you become the minister of culture?
如果是搖滾演唱會你就讓他去了。
You'd let him go if it was a rock 'n' roll concert.
- 對了！我會的。對。
- 難以置信。
- That's right! You bet I would. Yes.
- Unbelievable.
你神經錯亂了嗎？
Are you out of your mind?
我不會讓他去的，因為不安全
I'm not letting him go because it's not safe.
他又不至於暴露在整個沃特福德面前
He doesn't have to be on display for the entire community of Waterford.
而且就因為這不是搖滾演唱會
And because it's not rock and roll.
你以為你很可愛，爸爸，但你就是垃圾。
You think you're cute, Dad,but you're full of shit.
- 不要對我這樣講話。
- 為什麼？
- Don't talk to me like that.
- Why?
我們不應該質疑權威麼？你就是那麼教我的！
Aren't we supposed to question authority? You taught me that!
你以為你是誰？巴頓將軍？
Who do you think you are? General Patton?
為什麼上學對我來說還比去音樂會危險了？
Why is it any more dangerous for me to go to school than it is to go to the concert?
因為在學校還有600個孩子
Because there are 600 other kids at the school.
讓我歇會吧
Give me a break.
你不可以去。
You're not going.
曼菲爾德先生！我們有這樣的享受應該感謝什麼？
Mr. Manfield! To what do we owe this pleasure?
羅娜邀請的我。
Lorna invited me.
她通常沒這麼好的審美。
She usually doesn't show such good judgment.
我很高興。我想讓你見一些人。
I'm delighted. There's some people I want you to meet.
山姆，這是麥克·曼菲爾德，我和你說過的那個男孩
Sam, this is Michael Manfield,the boy I was telling you about.
- 很高興認識你。
- 你好
- Pleased to meet you.
- Hi.
也許我們可以讓你給我們彈點什麼
Perhaps we can convince you to play something for us.
我什麼都沒準備
I have nothing prepared.
有一天我聽見你在彈勃拉姆斯，真是美
I heard you working on some Brahms the other day. It was perfectly lovely.
第二次幕間休息之後你可以彈一彈
You can play it after the second intermission.
我很樂意，但是我真的要去朋友家接我弟弟
I'd like to, but I really have to go pick up my brother at a friend's house.
你可以在走之前彈。
You can play before you have to go.
聽著，爸爸，抱歉
Listen, Dad, would you excuse me?
我想帶麥克吃點東西
I'd like to get Michael something to eat.
- 希望早點聽到你演奏
- 真是好東西。
- Hope to hear you soon.
- It was really good stuff.
為什麼你不想為他們演奏？
How come you didn't want to play for them?
如果是我自己，我不會考慮。但是你會喜歡的。
Personally, I wouldn't consider it,but you're supposed to love this stuff.
沒關係，你不用解釋。莫扎特也是個瘋子。
It's all right. You don't have to explain.Mozart was crazy, too.
- 想上去去我的房間麼？
- 好。
- Want to go up to my room?
- Okay.
好啦。把牛奶喝完。
All right. Finish your milk.
抱歉
Excuse me.
吉他就是我的生命。
Guitar is my life.
你很讓人迷惑，你知道
You're very confusing, you know.
誰？我？為什麼？
Who, me? Why?
因為有的時候你那麼直接……
'Cause sometimes you can be so straight...
但有的時候，轉過身去你又是那樣的
and then other times, you turn around and you're like that.
- 總是說著「是，先生」或者「不是，先生」
- 我很禮貌的
-It's always, "Yes, sir" and "No, sir. "
- I'm polite.
- 禮貌很假。
- 不是假。
- Polite is phony.
- It's not phony.
- 可以避免衝突。
- 你現在就在做這個麼？
- It avoids confrontation.
- Is that what you're doing now?
你在避免衝突？
You're avoiding confrontation?
你就沒有想說「去他媽的」的時候？
Don't you ever want to say, "Cut the shit"?
羅娜！麥克和你在一起嗎？我想讓他出來演奏。
Lorna! Is Michael in there with you? I want him to play.
他走了。他去接他弟弟了
He left. He went to pick up his brother.
我以為這是我的房間
I thought this was my room.
你媽媽讓你下樓
Your mother wants you downstairs.
那有棵樹（可以從那出去）。
There's a tree.
鮑威爾太太？可以見醫生了。
Mrs. Powell? The doctor will see you now.
我把錢包落在這了嗎？
Did I leave my purse out here?
謝謝。
Thank you.
你好？
Excuse me?
你好！
Excuse me!
你有預約嗎？
Do you have an appointment?
沒有。
Nope.
格斯。
Gus!
吃什麼，媽媽？
What's cooking, mama?
我看著你，我就能看到你站在密歇根街角……
I look at you, and I can see you standing on the corner of Michigan Avenue...
穿著墨西哥式上衣，戴著那瘋癲的銀色東西
in a Mexican blouse and those crazy silver things.
大銀耳環
Big silver earrings.
天哪，那是好久以前了
God, that was a long time ago.
阿瑟怎麼樣？
How's Artie?
他挺好。
He's okay.
其實他好極了
He's great, actually.
他在佛羅里達的一處有毒垃圾堆放點做了點工作
He did some work in Florida on a toxic waste dump.
在這，他組織了個個食品公司
Here, he organized a food co-op...
他還在讓他的餐廳集團化
and he's trying to get his restaurant to unionize.
你和阿瑟怎麼樣
And how's you and Artie?
我們還好
We're okay.
我是說，你知道，很艱難
I mean, you know, it's hard.
我想你。
I think about you.
我想你
希望你是安全的
I hope you're safe.
你怎麼做到的？
How do you manage this?
有房子
Got a house...
兩個孩子
two kids.
就像你過著正常人的生活
It's kind of like you're leading a regular life.
我很會撒謊
I'm a good liar.
但是我累了
But I'm tired.
媽的
Shit.
哦，天
Oh, God.
嗨，大廚
Hey, chief.
你好
Hello.
你好？
Hello?
這個人開了八百英里來見你
That's all you got to say to this guy that just drove...
你就和他說一句你好？
800 miles out of his way to see you?
你看起來好極了
You look great.
為什麼我會感覺這麼不安？
Then how come I feel so uneasy?
阿瑟，我們去散步吧。我有事情要告訴你
Artie, let's take a walk.I got stuff to talk to you about.
我累了
I'm tired.
去吧，保羅。和他散散步。你有12年沒見他了。
Go ahead, Paul. Take a walk with him. You haven't seen him for 12 years.
你他媽的是瘋了！
You're out of your fucking mind!
- 你欠我們的！
- 我他媽的什麼都不欠你們。
- You owe us!
- I don't owe you a goddamn thing.
你知道你那混蛋朋友想讓我幹什麼嗎？
Do you know what your asshole friend here wants me to do?
搶銀行！你相信麼？他媽的銀行！
Rob a fucking bank! Can you believe it? A fucking bank!
他還說那是「政治運動」
A "political action," he calls it.
自由軍佈置給我們這個任務的
We've been assigned this little job by the Liberation Army.
別人都對他們有錯誤的印象，以為他們在支持我們……
Who are under the mistaken impression that they've been supporting us...
我們欠他們的！
and we owe them something!
你想讓我的孩子做什麼？
What do they want my kids to do?
推翻他媽的總統？
Knock off the fucking president?
你想讓我看看你車裡是什麼嗎？
You want to show what you got in your car?
沒什麼。我的東西。
Nothing. It's my stuff.
這可不是你給我的印象。
That's not the impression you gave me.
看看吧，怎麼樣？
Let's look, shall we?
讓孩子們過來。我想讓他們看看這個。
Get the kids down here.I want them to see this.
這人還他媽是個瘋子！
guy's still a fucking maniac!
閉嘴吧
Just stop it.
孩子們！過來！就現在！
Boys! Get down here! Now!
我想讓你們知道，我們不動槍
I want you to know guns are not what we're about.
現在，回屋裡去
Now, get back in the house.
你會改變世界的，阿瑟……
You're going to change the world, Artie...
就組織一下那幾個小食品公司？
by organizing these little food co-ops?
我要出去。
I'm going out.
你晚上可以留下……
You can stay the night...
但等我回來，我可不想看見這些槍在我孩子周圍十公里以內。
but when I get back, I don't want to see these things within 10 miles of my kids.
安妮，我想解釋
Annie, I'd like to explain this.
我在聽。
I'm listening.
你知道，我們在地下狀態已經很久了
You know, we've been under a long time.
很多不好的事情發生了。很多不好的事情還在發生。
A lot of bad shit has happened. A lot of bad shit keeps happening.
但是整個世界都以為
But we're dead...
我們已經死了
as far as the world is concerned.
我們採取一個行動，報紙就埋沒一個
We pull an action and they bury it in the newspapers.
就好像什麼都沒發生過
It's like it didn't happen.
只有在什麼東西或者什麼人被吹走了
The only time the pigs or the media pay attention...
那豬一樣的媒體才會引起注意
is when something or somebody gets blown away.
好。如果打不敗他們，就加入他們。
Great. If you can't beat them, join them.
你覺得我們採取非暴力，會取得勝利麼？
Do you think we're going to win this by turning the other cheek?
要是能這樣，你怎麼不試試在水上走？
Why don't you try walking on water?
你怎麼還不長大呢？我們贏不了的。
Why don't you try growing up? There's nothing to win.
戰爭一結束，它已經結束了。
It was over as soon as the war ended.
戰爭沒有結束，安妮。它永遠不會結束。
The war didn't end, Annie.The war ain't never going to end.
和政治或者我車裡的貨無關。
This has nothing to do with politics or the merchandise in my car.
只是阿瑟發火了
This is just Artie's pissed.
阿瑟發火了……
Artie's pissed...
是因為他嫉妒。
'cause Artie's jealous.
他嫉妒……
And Artie's jealous...
是因為你想要我。
because you want me.
我當然也想要你
And I sure want you.
這狀況真糟糕。
That's a bad situation.
遲早它們都會爆炸
Sooner or later, they're just going to blow up.
你知道，我為你感到遺憾
You know, I feel sorry for you.
真的。
I do.
你46歲了，還像個嬰兒
You're a 46-year-old infant.
什麼都得按著你的想法來，是不是？什麼時候都是，什麼地方都是
Everything has to be your way, doesn't it? When you want it, where you want it.
你不是革命者
You're not a revolutionary.
這比玩槍或者玩弄自己要求更高
That requires more than playing with guns or with yourself.
需要同情心，需要紀律
It requires compassion, discipline.
你在評判我麼？
Are you judging me?
女士，你在評判你自己。
You judge yourself, lady.
你過得就像那種傻乎乎的中產階級的郊區家庭主婦
You're living like some kind of silly-ass, middle-class, suburban housewife.
你活在謊言之中……
You're living a lie...
就像你說的那樣。
just like you said.
你為什麼不把諾曼·洛克威爾一家供出來？
Why don't you take this little Norman Rockwell family and turn them in?
聯邦調查局會很樂意抓到他們的。
The feds would be glad to get them.
這樣你就可以脫身了。
And then you could get the fuck out.
我倒希望我能。
I wish I could.
出去吧。
Now get out.
你還好麼，媽媽
Are you okay, Mom?
嗯。
Yeah.
好。
Fine.
睡覺吧。
Go to bed.
我不是保羅！我不是保羅！我是……
I am not Paul. I am not Paul! I am-
- 進來，保羅。
- 我不是保羅！
- Paul, come in.
- I'm not Paul.
我是阿瑟
I'm Arthur.
別叫我「保羅」。我是阿瑟。
Don't call me "Paul. " I am Arthur.
我是阿瑟·艾利·波普！
I am Arthur Eli Pope!
- 爸爸怎麼了？
- 他剛喝多了。
- What's the matter with Dad?
- He's just had a lot to drink.
1944年7月16日出生在紐約州的普拉茨堡！
Born in Plattsburg, New York, July 16, 1944!
美國公民……我母親……
A US citizen. My mother's...
娘家姓是希爾伯維茨。
maiden name is Silbowitz.
我父親真名是波波夫。莫裡斯·波波夫。
My father's real name is Popov.Morris Popov.
我駕駛證號碼是4-3-5-7...
My driver's license number is 4-3-5-7...
1-1。
1-1.
我入伍時候的號碼是M-S-8-9...
My draft number is M-S-8-9...
- 3-5-8-4.
- 好了。
-3-5-8-4.
- It's okay.
我叫波普。
My name is Pope.
沒事了。
It's okay.
你說要散步，又不是遠足。
You said walk, not hike.
- 你累了？
- 不是。
- Are you tired?
- No.
- 很美。
- 是啊。
-It's beautiful.
- Yeah.
你知道，當你約我的時候我真的很驚訝
You know, I was really surprised when you called me.
為什麼？
Why?
我不確定你是不是喜歡我
I wasn't sure if you liked me or not.
有的時候你那麼……
Sometimes you're so...
我也不確定你是不是也很喜歡我。
I'm not too sure if you like me too much, either.
相信吧。我可不會跟著一個我不喜歡的人走上十英里
Take it on faith. I usually don't follow people I don't like for 10 miles...
一直走到樹林中間
into the middle of the woods.
你怎麼這麼生氣？
Why are you so angry?
那是風趣，不是生氣
That's wit, not anger.
- 你嚇到很多人。
- 除了你還有誰？
- You scare a lot of people.
- Who, besides you?
很多人嚇到我。
A lot of people scare me.
誰嚇到你？
Who scares you?
像我父母一樣和善的人
People who are nice, like my parents.
和善的人有什麼錯？
What's wrong with being nice?
這樣說吧。
Let's put it like this.
我母親真的很好。
My mother is really nice.
她從來不做任何錯事或者刻薄的事
She never does anything wrong or mean.
她甚至把舊衣服給僕人
She even gives her old clothe to the maid...
但她真的不想認識她
but she doesn't really want to know her.
十年裡她連貝蒂的丈夫都沒見過
In 10 years,she's never even seen Betty's husband.
他來接她的時候都在車裡等著
He waits in the car when he comes to pick her up.
你父親一定不像這樣
Your father's sure not like that.
為什麼？因為他在課上放麥當娜的歌？
Why? Because he plays Madonna in class?
他除了知道你彈琴很棒，還知道什麼？
What does he know about you, except that you're good on the piano?
他們只看到他們想看的東西，把別的都屏蔽掉
They see what they want to see,and they block out everything else...
尤其是可能不太好的東西
especially if it might not be nice.
他們好像並不很習慣你的方式
They don't seem to get in your way much.
我父母？他們的方式就是不相信我真正的樣子
My parents? It's just their way of not believing who I really am.
他們覺得最終我會變成
They think that eventually,I'll turn back into the little girl...
鋼琴上的照片裡那穿著粉色裙子的小女孩
in the pink dress that's in the picture on the piano.
那你覺得呢？
And what do you think?
你真的想知道？
You really want to know?
你覺得我會去紐約學寫作
I think that I'll go to New York and learn to write...
每個聖誕節回家
and that I'll come home every Christmas...
大家都對我很禮貌
and everyone will be really polite.
聽起來沒那麼壞。
That's doesn't sound so bad.
也許是，但是我還沒真正在紐約
Maybe not, but I'm not in New York yet.
那你呢？
So what about you?
我完全不瞭解你
I don't know a thing about you.
你可能會完好地從宙斯的腦袋裡鑽出來（指雅典娜）
You might as well have sprung full-grown out of the head of Zeus.
那你父母呢？奧茲和哈里特？（電影《奧茲和哈里特的冒險》，奧茲和哈里特生活在數字時代）
Who are your parents? Ozzie and Harriet?
是啊，有時候是這樣
Yeah, sometimes.
我是不是得去見見他們，看看你為什麼這麼完美？
Do I get to meet them and see how you came out so perfect?
我的意思是，這樣才公平
I mean, it seems only fair.
我讓你看我的，你讓我看你的
I showed you mine, you show me yours.
我猜這就結束休息了吧
I guess this is the end of the rest stop.
我說什麼來著？
What did I say?
我以為下面會好一些
I thought it would be nicer down here.
你沒傳達太多信息
You don't transmit too much information.
什麼？
What?
我說，你沒傳達太多信息
I said, you don't transmit too much information.
對不起。
Sorry.
你夏天要幹什麼？
What are you doing over the summer?
我在加油站找了份工作
I have a job pumping gas.
你終於讓最高法院聽你的了，嗯？
You finally got the Supreme Court to hear your case, huh?
你呢？
What about you?
不知道。
I don't know.
你覺得在這更好？
You thought it'd be nicer over here?
嗯
Yeah.
你在幹什麼
What are you doing?
找點什麼送我媽媽生日禮物
I'm looking for something for my mom's birthday.
你的意思是說，萬一有人偶爾在沙灘上丟了
You mean, in case somebody happened to leave...
一個Cuisinart（美國廚具品牌）的東西或者一個鑽石戒指？
a Cuisinart or a diamond ring lying on the beach?
是啊，那就行。必須得是你做的，或者是你找到的東西。
Yeah, that would qualify. It has to be omething either you make or find.
- 她生日是什麼時候？
- 下周。
- When's her birthday?
- Next week.
真美。
That's beautiful.
給你媽媽的。
It's for your mother.
你送給她。
You give it to her.
好
Okay.
在那一定更好。
It must be nicer over there.
過來，切這些。
Here, chop these.
不對，不對，不對。看。你到一邊去。
No, no, no. Watch. Move.
拿著刀……
You hold the knife...
就這麼做。
and you just do that.
很乾淨。我試試
That's neat. Let me try.
不，不。我是個素食者，我可不想你把你的小手指頭切到菜裡去。
No, no. I'm a vegetarian. I don't want pieces of tiny little fingers in my stew.
這。你來攪拌。
Here. You stir.
你在等誰嗎？
Were you expecting someone?
嗨。
Hi.
我是羅娜。
I'm Lorna.
麥克邀請了我。
Michael invited me.
好吧，進來吧
Well, come in.
你朋友在這
Your friend's here.
嗨
Hi.
- 嗨。
- 我可以幫忙麼？
- Hi.
- Can I help?
不用，不用，沒關係。謝謝。
No. No, it's okay. Thank you.
你切到手指了。
You cut your finger.
是啊
Yeah.
這是你女朋友？
Is this your girlfriend?
嗨，我是史蒂芬。
Hi, I'm Stephen.
真好吃，寶貝。完全超出你的水平
That was delicious, babe.You outdid yourself.
為我自己的安格魯-撒克遜教徒準備的朝聖食物。
This pilgrim food for my very own WASP.
但是你得原諒我，親愛的
But you must forgive me, my darling.
我沒法做出這種果凍模具
I couldn't get myself to make one of those Jell-O molds.
這次就原諒你了
You're forgiven this time.
現在，（法語）
And now, for the pi鎗e de r閟istance.
- 我來，爸爸
- 你被逮捕了
- Let me, Dad.
- You're under arrest.
看看，你弄得肚臍那到處都是
Look at this.You got it all over your bellybutton.
看看
Look at that.
哦天哪。我老得都能把這房子弄著火。
Oh, God. I'm old enough to set the house on fire.
抱歉，我以為你媽媽叫辛西婭。
I'm sorry, I thought your mother's name was Cynthia.
過生日的時候我們都叫山姆
On birthdays, we're all Sam.
這是我們家小小的傳統……
It's a little family tradition...
是因為我1968年那次超棒的用迷幻劑的經歷
resulting from a particularly good LSD trip I took in 1968.
再來點酒？
More wine?
- 你能讓我歇會麼？
- 在歐洲，小孩子就能喝酒。
- Would you give me a break?
- In Europe, kids drink wine.
在我給「匿名酗酒者（美國一家幫助戒酒的機構）」打電話（指喝醉）之前，把給你媽媽的禮物拿來。
Get your mother her present before I call Alcoholics Anonymous.
謝謝
Thanks.
這就是我想要的
It's just what I wanted.
- 真的？
- 千真萬確
- Really?
- Absolutely.
那是什麼，蝴蝶？
What is that, a butterfly?
不是，是個鯨魚，當做禮物了
No, it's a whale of a present.
- 謝謝
- 我會彈奏它的
- Thanks.- I'll play it for you sometime.
這是羅娜的禮物
This is from Lorna.
真美
That's beautiful.
謝謝你，羅娜
Thank you, Lorna.
我的禮物，等會給你
Mine, you get later.
你保證
You bet.
沒問題
On your feet!
我來幫忙。
Let me help.
我喜歡她。
I like her.
嗯？
Yeah?
- 我也喜歡她。
- 我知道
- I like her, too.- I know.
你確定這是菲利普斯家的孩子？
You sure this is the Phillips' kid?
你在醫院沒被掉包吧，嗯？
They didn't switch you at the hospital,or anything, did they?
你知道，我不敢想像他們有多不可理喻。
You know, I can't believe how incredible they are.
你知道如果我給我媽媽一個貝殼當做生日禮物，她會怎麼做？
Do you know what my mother would do if I gave her a shell for her birthday?
沒關係吧
They're okay.
那就是你，害怕承認自己
That's you all over,afraid to commit yourself.
我以為這就是我
I thought it was just me.
和你在一起我很開心
I'm very happy with you.
我也是
I'm very happy with you, too.
沒關係，我想這樣
It's okay, I want to.
- 你沒去上廚藝課
- 你注意到了。
- You weren't in cooking.
- You noticed.
- 你去哪了？
- 我翹課了
- Where were you?- I cut.
- 為什麼？
- 我不想見你。
- Why?- I didn't want to see you.
曼菲爾德，我能和你說幾句話麼
Manfield, could I talk to you for a minute?
你沒必要這麼緊張。就算你做了錯事……
You don't have to look so anxious.If you've done something wrong...
我也不知道。我只是想知道你對大學的計劃。
I don't know about it. I just want to talk to you about your college plans.
我想休息一年，也許去歐洲旅行，聽聽音樂。
I was thinking of taking a year off, maybe traveling to Europe, listening to music.
我不能要求你做什麼，但是我覺得你應該申請大學
I can't tell you what to do, but I think you ought to make an application, anyway.
你可以推遲入學的
You can always postpone entry.
我想讓你考慮考慮申請朱利亞德（紐約一所藝術學院）
I'd like you to consider applying to Juilliard.
提前錄取
Early admission.
我看了你成績的檔案，被錄取應該沒問題
I looked at your academic records.You should have no trouble getting in.
不過，剩下的呢？
Where's the rest of it, by the way?
你的檔案裡沒有原先的學校的。
There's nothing in your file from your old school.
我們搬家的時候弄丟了。
It was lost when we moved.
找回來的時候，我想看看。
When it comes through, I'd like to see it.
同時，你看看這個。
In the meantime, you look at that.
我會樂意給你寫推薦信的。
I'd be happy to write you a letter of recommendation.
謝謝
Thank you.
看完之後還給我
Get back to me when you've looked at it.
你不和我說話
You wouldn't talk to me.
現在，起床
Now, get up.
下樓，從後門出去
Go down the stairs and out the back door.
悄悄的
Be quiet.
我就在你後面。
I'll be right behind you.
我光著腳呢
I'm barefoot.
坐下
Sit down.
我在幹嘛？
What am I doing?
我就是想和你說話。
I just wanted to talk to you.
你那天在學校不聽我講。
You wouldn't listen, the other day at school.
我那天晚上沒和你在一起，不是因為我不想。
I couldn't stay with you that night. Not because I didn't want to.
如果你想回去，對我來說沒什麼。
If you want to go back, it's fine with me.
- 你是個笨蛋。
- 不。
- You're a bully.- No.
我說了謊。
I'm a liar.
我真名不是麥克
My name isn't Michael.
是丹尼。
It's Danny.
我父母是阿瑟和安妮·波普
My parents are Arthur and Annie Pope.
1971年他們因為讓汽油彈實驗室爆炸，和聯邦調查局惹上了麻煩
They're in trouble with the FBl for blowing up a napalm lab in 1971.
有一個人差點就死了
There was a man who was almost killed.
那是個看門人，當時不該在那的
A janitor,abcwho wasn't supposed to be there.
我們在所有生日蛋糕上都寫「山姆」
We put "Sam" on the birthday cakes, on all the birthday cakes...
是因為每到一個地方，我們就換新名字
because we change our names every time we move.
從我兩歲起，就一直這樣了
I've been doing this since I was two.
我不知道別的辦法。
I don't know any other way.
我只是想告訴你我很抱歉
I just wanted to tell you that I was sorry.
我想解釋我為什麼說不了太多事
I wanted to explain why I can't talk about a lot of things.
比如大學。我不能去上大學。我不能離開他們。
Like college. I can't go to college.I can't leave them.
我還想告訴你……
And I wanted to tell you...
我為什麼不能和你在一起。
why I couldn't be with you.
不能讓你不知道。我不想對你說謊。
Not without your knowing.I didn't want to lie to you.
現在我沒權利和你說這些的
Now, I have no right in telling this to you.
對你，對他們，都很危險。
It's dangerous for you,and it's dangerous for them.
對不起，我只是控制不住自己
I'm sorry. I just couldn't stop myself.
你想做什麼都可以做，你可以告訴你爸爸。我不介意
You can do what you want to. You can tell your dad anything. I don't care.
我只是想要你知道
I just needed you to know.
我不知道我在做什麼
I don't know what I'm doing.
我愛你
And I love you.
I love you.
那我要叫你什麼？
What do I call you?
麥克。什麼都不用變
Michael. Nothing changes.
他們真的不想讓你上大學麼？
They really don't want you to go to school, huh?
我們還沒有談
We haven't talked about it.
- 我不能問他們
- 為什麼不？
- I can't ask them.- Why not?
那就意味著拆散整個家庭，我再也見不到他們。
It would mean breaking up the family,not seeing them again.
他們除了我們，什麼都沒有
They don't have anything else.
我不能相信他們會要求你耗費自己的生命去陪著他們
I can't believe that they'd want you to give up your whole life to stay with them.
和他們談。他們會理解的。
Talk to them. They'll understand.
你有很多秘密，不是麼
You have a lot of secrets, don't you?
現在你又多了一個。
Now you have another one.
去和羅娜約會了？
Been to see Lorna?
我喜歡她。
I like that one.
她很活潑
She's full of beans.
你真心喜歡她，不是麼
You really like her, don't you?
聰明的人總是最好的
The smart ones are always the best.
你和她睡了麼？
Are you sleeping with her?
- 嗯。
- 好。
- Yeah.
- Okay.
快去，睡覺去。明天還要上學。
Go ahead, hit the sack.You got school tomorrow.
你在停止專業鋼琴之後
How long have you been playing violin...
演奏了多久小提琴？
after you stopped playing seriously piano?
大概五年
About five years.
什麼時候來美國的？
When did you come to the States?
1980年
In 1980.
好的，非常感謝
All right. Thank you very much.
曼菲爾德先生，我們準備好面試你了。
Mr. Manfield. We're ready for you now.
你說你和誰學的？
Who did you say you studied with?
愛德華·菲利普斯
Edward Phillips.
- 在哪？
- 沃特福德。
- Where was this?- Waterford.
- 新澤西？
- 對
- New Jersey?- That's right.
我們好像沒有你的學校檔案
We seem not to have all your school records.
我以前的學校有，但是丟了
There was a school fire at my old school, and the records were lost.
今年我們剛搬到新澤西
We only moved to New Jersey this year.
所以你和菲利普斯先生只學了很短時間
So you've only studied with Mr. Phillipsfor a short time.
是的，太太
Yes, ma'am.
你還和誰學過？
Who else have you worked with?
很多不同的，但沒有一個這麼重要
A lot of different people.No one important.
我們經常搬家
We move a lot.
你必須給我們你的SAT成績，還有……
You'll have to supply us with SAT scores and...
我們必須要那些檔案
we'll have to have those records.
曼菲爾德先生。
Mr. Manfield.
哦，對不起
Oh, sorry.
你很有才華，你知道
You are very talented, you know.
謝謝，太太
Thank you, ma'am.
給帕特森太太的芝士比薩。
A cheese pizza for Mrs. Patterson.
帕特森太太沒訂比薩。
I don't think Mrs. Patterson ordered a pizza.
這是莫裡山68434號麼?
Is this Murray Hill 68434?
- 是
- 那有人定了比薩。
- Yes.- Someone ordered it.
稍等。
這比薩是怎麼回事？
你訂了一個。
You ordered one.
我沒有。
I didn't.
那你得付錢麼？
Will you have to pay for it?
不，我得吃
No, I'll have to eat it.
我真的不在乎。等等。你下次不能敲門麼？
I really don't care. Hold on.Could you knock next time?
- 對不起。
- 聽著，我得走了。嗯。拜拜
- I'm sorry.- Listen, I have to go. Yeah. Bye.
我在想麥克有沒有和你提到……
I was wondering if Michael had ever mentioned anything to you...
他以前的學校
about his old school.
不多。怎麼問這個？
Not much. Why?
都沒把他的檔案寄來。
They never sent his records.
然後呢？
So?
我打電話給學校，說沒有他的檔案。
I called the school.They have no record of him.
有可能是電腦刪掉了，或者什麼的。
They probably got eaten by a computer,or something.
在肯塔基州的藍山，沒有電腦的
They don't have a computer in Blue Hill, Kentucky.
你研究他做什麼？
What are you on his case for?
- 我們對他一無所知。
- 嗯，他以前是個殺人犯
- We know nothing about him.- So, he's an axe murderer.
我說，拜託！我以為他是你教過的音樂最好的學生。
I mean, come on! I thought he was the best music student you ever had.
他是，但這解釋不了他檔案丟失的問題
He is, but that doesn't explain his missing records.
如果你想知道他究竟是誰，為什麼不直接找他談？
If you want to know who he is, why don't you talk to him?
他是個人！
He's a person!
他不是電腦裡的數據
He's not a computer printout!
能不能把門關上？
Would you please close the door?
- 曼菲爾德太太？
- 是
- Mrs. Manfield?- Yes.
- 謝謝你能來
- 您好
- Thank you for coming.- How do you do?
- 要不要來點咖啡？
- 不，謝謝
- Would you like some coffee?- No, thanks.
我想和您聊聊麥克
I want to talk to you about Michael.
我不想在學校見，這樣他就不知道我們談過
I didn't want to meet at school,because he doesn't know we're talking.
但是他最近很失落也很緊張
But he's been upset lately, and nervous.
我以為可能是家裡出了點事
I thought maybe there was something at home.
沒有
No.
我知道這是私人事情。我只是覺得如果我知道的話，我能幫得上忙。
I know these things are private. I just thought maybe I could help, if I knew.
但是真的什麼事都沒有。
But there isn't anything. Really.
也許他擔心朱利亞德。
Maybe he's worried about Juilliard.
朱利亞德？
Juilliard?
您知道他的計劃？
You know about his plans?
- 是啊，當然
- 您不反對？
- Yeah, sure.- And you don't object?
不反對
No.
他們對他的面試印象深刻
They were very impressed with his audition.
他們打算一拿到他的檔案就錄取他
They're prepared to take him, just as soon as they get his records.
那時候他就得去了，是不是？
He'll have to go then, won't he?
是不是經濟困難？
Is there a financial problem?
我們可不像洛克菲勒家族那麼有錢。
We're not the Rockefellers.
他可能會擔心錢的問題
He could be worried about that.
我們還過得下去。
We always manage.
有獎學金的。他可以拿
There are scholarships. He could get one.
他很有才華
He's very talented.
我們也許不富裕，但我們關心孩子
We may not have a lot, but we care about our kids.
我當然知道您關心
I'm sure you do.
我只是想知道他有過專業的老師麼？
I was just wondering,has he ever had a serious teacher?
他是怎樣達到這個水平的？
How has he gotten this far?
我不知道
I don't know.
他在這學一點，那學一點。我們經常搬家。為什麼問這個
He's picked up a little here and there.We move around a lot. Why?
我給藍山打了電話，沒有麥克·曼菲爾德的檔案
I called Blue Hill and they have no record of Michael Manfield.
那是因為他在那註冊的時候沒有用曼菲爾德這個名字
That's because he wasn't registered there under Manfield.
你看，我以前結過婚，保羅收養了他
See, I was married before,and Paul adopted him.
但是直到今年才能合法地跟他的姓
But it took until just this year to adopt his name legally.
在藍山，他跟的是我前夫的姓
He's under my old husband's name at Blue Hill.
沒有這些檔案，他不能完成申請
He can't finish his application without those records.
我會拿到的
I'll get them.
你必須得拿，因為他們只把檔案給家長……
You'll have to, because they won't release them to anyone but a parent-
我說了，我會拿到的。行了麼？
I said, I'll get them. All right?
- 現在，我得走了
- 好的，當然
- Now, if you'll excuse me.
- Yeah, sure.
怎麼了，媽媽？
What's wrong, Mom?
沒什麼
Nothing.
我愛你
I just love you.
我要去接你爸爸
I've got to pick up your father.
喜歡麼？我把貨車賣了，買了這個。我覺得這樣更實際一點。
Do you like it? I traded the van in for it.Thought it'd be more practical.
而且，這讓他們一直猜測
Besides, it keeps them guessing.
怎麼了，山姆？
What's up, Sam?
別那麼叫我
Don't call me that.
好吧
Okay.
丹尼去申請大學了
Danny's applied to college.
在哪？
Where?
朱利亞德
Juilliard.
你怎麼知道的？
How do you know?
菲利普斯。他想讓他去
Phillips. He wants him to go.
他為什麼不離咱們家的事遠點？
Why doesn't he keep his goddamn nose out of our business?
因為他覺得他很有才華。
Because he thinks he's talented.
丹尼告訴你這些了麼？
Has Danny told you about any of this?
沒有。
No.
我們要怎麼做？
What are we going to do?
媽的
Shit.
去他媽的！
Goddamn fucking shit!
他為什麼不能去上大學？
Why can't he go?
因為如果他去了，我們就再也見不到他了。
Because we'll never see him again if he does.
為什麼不能？我們可以安排和他見面。
Why? We could arrange to meet him.
你想這樣？
Is that what you want?
在機場休息室見十分鐘，然後聯邦調查局一輩子跟在他屁股後面？
Ten minutes at an airport lounge, and the FBl all over his ass the rest of the time?
你想讓他像我父母一樣站在電話亭，洗衣房……
You want him standing in phone booths and Laundromats like my parents...
只能通過通信網絡和我們聯繫？我不想這樣。
only connecting with us through the network? I don't think so.
如果他去了，我們就再也見不到他了
If he goes,we're never going to see him again...
我不能接受。
and that is unacceptable to me.
我連想都不會想。
I never even let myself think about this.
我真傻。
I was so stupid.
我只想讓我們在一起
All I wanted was that we would be together.
我應該把丹尼扔給我媽媽的
We should have left Danny with my mother.
- 我們都不該有哈利
- 閉嘴。
- We never should have had Harry.- Stop it.
我不能這樣，阿瑟。看看我們對孩子都做了些什麼。
I can't, Arthur.Look what we're doing to these kids.
他們一輩子都像罪犯一樣在逃亡。
They've been running their whole lives like criminals.
他們什麼都沒做！
And they didn't do anything!
這不公平
It isn't fair.
我知道這他媽的不公平。
I know it isn't goddamned fair.
他們經過了一些衝擊，但是你這樣逼自己於事無補
They've taken some bumps, but it's not going to help anything to beat yourself up.
看看他們，看在上帝的份上。
Look at them, for God's sake.
看看這些孩子。他們多麼優秀
Look at those kids. They're magnificent.
他們很美
They're beautiful.
很聰明很體貼
And bright. Caring.
我們能做得多壞呢？
How badly could we have done?
我們應該自首
We should turn ourselves in.
然後接下來15年都呆在監獄裡……
So we can sit in prison for the next 15 years...
從鐵窗裡看我們的孩子們？
and look at the kids through bars?
每次還只能看一個小時
You can only get through this one day, one hour at a time.
我就準備這麼做。
That's what I'm doing.
丹尼已經長大了。
And Danny's all grown up.
我們該放他走了
We have to let him go.
這顆牙疼死我了
This tooth is killing me.
我覺得補的東西掉了。該去看看喬納。
I think I lost a filling. Better go see Jonah.
我會坐公交車。
I'll take a bus.
- 你去市內的時候我總是擔心
- 為什麼？
- I always worry when you go into the city.- Why?
因為在那他們誰都能看見
Because that's where they get everyone.
很安靜。
It's been quiet.
有時候太安靜了
Sometimes it gets too quiet.
你還記得孩子小時候你常說的話麼？
Remember what you used to say when the kids were small?
「別著急，除非你什麼都聽不見了。」
"Don't worry unless you don't hear anything. "
小心點，好不好？
Be careful, all right?
我什麼都沒看見。X光片裡也什麼都沒有。
I don't see anything. And there's nothing on the x-ray.
我沒在抱怨。
I'm not complaining.
還需要什麼嗎？
You need anything else?
不，謝謝。我們很好。我在為一個全科醫生工作。
No, thanks. We're okay. I'm working for a GP.
現金可以嗎？
How about cash?
可以
Okay.
如果你提前告訴我，我可以安排更多的
If you'd give me some notice, I could arrange to have more.
不。很好了。謝謝
No. This is great. Thanks.
- 你總是讓我覺得這麼愧疚。
- 為什麼？
- You always make me feel so guilty. - Why?
這就是你的生活方式。
You're living it.
是啊，我猜我是。
Yeah, I guess I am.
喬納，我需要你幫我打個電話
Jonah, I need youabcto make a phone call for me.
當然可以
Of course.
夫人？
Madame?
嗨，爸爸
Hi, Dad.
我讓喬納做的這個
I asked Jonah to set this up.
如果你想，可以叫警察
You can call the cops if you want to.
對不起。
I'm sorry.
這對我也很難
This is hard for me, too.
- 夫人要點什麼飲料？
- 不，謝謝
- Will madame have a drink?- No, thank you.
我想知道14年不見你的孩子
I wonder if you'll ever know what it's like...
是什麼感覺
not to see your child for 14 years.
連他是死是活都不知道
Not knowing whether she's living or dead.
不知道這孩子是不是
Not knowing whether that child...
要對別人的死亡或者傷殘負責
is responsible for the death and mutilation of other human beings.
要不要讓你自己
Whether to hold yourself responsible...
為那死亡或傷殘負責任
for that death and mutilation...
因為扣動扳機，引爆炸彈的是你的孩子
because it is your child who is pulling the triggers, setting the bombs.
我沒殺任何人
I didn't kill anybody.
我不是來為自己辯護或是談政治的
I didn't come here to defend myself or to talk politics.
如果你不相信我當時那麼做是出於良心要結束戰爭
If you don't believe by now that what I did was an act of conscience to stop the war...
那我說什麼你都不會明白
then there's nothing I can say to you that's going to make you understand.
一個人失明，還殘疾了
A man was blinded and paralyzed.
他本不該在那的。
He wasn't supposed to be there.
你不覺得，有些時候
Don't you think there have been times...
我寧願讓自己失明，讓自己殘疾，來挽回這一切麼？
that I would have blinded and paralyzed myself to take that back?
那都是阿瑟的影響。
It's all Arthur's influence.
不，爸爸，不是
No, Dad, it isn't.
是我的主意。
It was my idea.
我活在我自己的選擇帶來的後果中
I'm living with the consequences of my own choice.
- 我不信。
- 那是你的問題
- I don't believe it.- Well, that's your problem.
你媽媽和我……
Your mother and me...
你為我們考慮過麼？
Do you think about us?
- 你非得這麼問麼
- 對。
- Do you really have to ask that?- Yes.
上一次我記得你對我說
The last thing I remember you saying to me...
我是個帝國主義的蠢豬
was that I was an imperialist pig...
一個人為了戰爭，貧窮和種族主義承擔責任
personally responsible for the war, the spread of poverty, racism.
- 我還年輕
- 是
- I was young.- Yes.
你還年輕
You were young.
有才華
And talented.
美麗
And beautiful.
那麼充滿了愛
And so full of love.
上帝啊，安妮。你為什麼把它們都拋棄了？
My God, Annie.Why did you throw it all away?
你媽媽很想你。還有丹尼
Your mother misses you terribly. And Danny.
你會收留他麼，爸爸
Will you take him, Dad?
他想學音樂
He wants to study music.
他很好
He's good.
他們想讓他去朱利亞德
They want him at Juilliard.
就像他們當時想讓你一樣
Just like they wanted you.
你還有那個用來練習的板？
Do you still have that practice board?
一直到現在。丹尼就是在那上面學會彈琴。
So far. Danny learned to play piano on it.
你教他的？
So you taught him?
不覺得這有點諷刺麼？
There's some irony in this, don't you think?
你現在在這
Here you are...
求我把丹尼帶到
asking me to take Danny...
你曾經唯恐避之不及的人生裡
into a life that you ran from like a shot out of hell.
他真的想要麼？
Is this what he wants?
我覺得是
I think so.
他沒告訴我就自己去了面試
He got himself an audition without telling me.
他會需要錢和照顧他的人
He'll need money, and people to care for him.
你不覺得你要的太多了麼？
Don't you think this is too much to ask?
我幾乎不認識這男孩
I hardly know the boy.
如果我們收留了他
If we take him...
那我們去哪都會有聯邦調查局的人跟著
there'd be FBl agents following us everywhere we go.
你就再也見不到他
You'd never be able to see him.
我們太老了，不能這麼做了
We're too old for this.
嗯，我覺得我要的太多了
Yeah, I think it's too much to ask.
我還有一個兒子
I have another son.
他十歲。叫哈利。
He's 10. Harry.
我在新聞上聽說了
I heard about it on the news.
我打算
I plan to turn myself in...
在他再也不需要我的時候就去自首，在他足夠大的時候
when he doesn't need me anymore.When he's old enough.
阿瑟呢？
And Arthur?
我不能為他說話
I can't speak for him.
請你考慮考慮
Please think about this.
我該走了
I should go.
安妮。
Annie.
他可以來我們家
He can come to us.
請您告訴媽媽，我愛她
Please, tell Mom that I love her.
我經常想你倆
And I've thought about you both so often.
我把你叫出來。
I've called out to you.
對不起我給你們帶來這麼多痛苦
I'm sorry that I've caused you so much pain.
我猜我要知道這是什麼感覺了
I guess I'm about to see what it feels like.
我愛你，爸爸
I love you, Dad.
我去見了我父親
I saw my father.
你什麼？
You what?
我見了唐納德
I saw Donald.
你就那麼走進他辦公室坐在他桌邊？
You just walked into his office and sat down at his desk?
沒有
No.
我在「小鍋」和他吃了午飯
I had lunch with him at La Petite Marmite.
幹什麼？
What for?
想看看他要不要收留丹尼.
To see if he'd take Danny.
收留丹尼？
Take Danny?
這樣他就可以上大學了
So he can go to college.
你開玩笑吧
You're kidding.
他說他會的
He said he would.
他說他會？
He said he would?
你知不知道會發生什麼？
You know what could have happened?
菲利普斯要你這麼做的？
Did Phillips put you up to this?
沒人要求我這麼做
Nobody put me up to this.
和菲利普斯無關。這是為了丹尼。
It's not about Phillips. It's about Danny.
他想去。他申請了，去了面試。
He wants to go. He applied.He went to an audition.
- 他他媽的去哪了？
- 朱利亞德
- He went fucking where?- Juilliard.
我不相信我的耳朵。
I don't believe my ears.
就給他一次機會吧。
Just give him a chance.
我要給黛博拉打電話，看看她能不能假造些檔案
I'm going to call Deborah and see if she can make him up some records.
為什麼？
Why?
因為菲力普斯給我填在申請表上的學校打了電話Because Phillips called the school I put on the registration form...
然後他們告訴他沒有叫麥克·曼菲爾德的人
and they told him there was no Michael Manfield.
會沒事的。
It's going to be okay.
他可以及時做好檔案的。阿瑟！
He can get records made up in time. Artie!
我們要搬了，孩子們
We're moving base camp, kids.
再呆幾天，我們就走。
We have a few days, and we're gone.
把蹤跡都銷毀掉。
Cover your tracks.
聽見沒？
You hear me?
你有想告訴我的事麼？
You have anything you want to tell me?
沒有。
No.
好。
Good.
我爸爸想要搬走。
My father wants to move on.
為什麼？
Why?
他有眼見。
He gets a sense.
就那樣？
Just like that?
就那樣。
Just like that.
什麼時候？
When?
隨時。
Anytime.
你就那麼消失了？
You'll just disappear?
那我們怎麼辦？
What about us?
- 他們需要我。
- 我需要你！
- They need me.- I need you!
你沒和他們談？
You didn't talk to them?
你不能一直逃離你沒有責任的事
You can't keep running from something you had nothing to do with.
你應該有你自己的機會
You deserve your own chance.
- 我想和你談談
- 沒什麼可談的
- I want to talk to you.- There's nothing to talk about.
菲利普斯知道的太多了
Phillips knows too much.
你在讓你的情感影響你的判斷。
You were letting your feelings affect your judgment.
而且，這就是上學
Besides, it's academic.
沒人會說的
Nobody will talk.
你不知道。
You don't know that.
他們能抓的都會抓。
They're going to try to pick up everyone they can now.
我們在這的日子到頭了。
We're finished here.
- 我們可以慢慢收手的，不是麼？
- 我們必須走了
- We can close up shop slowly, can't we?- We'll have to.
不然就會引起注意
Otherwise we'll attract attention.
大家都去上班和上學，等接下來的通知
Everybody goes to work and school until further notice.
如果有問題我們就在80號公路附近的野餐區見面
If there's a problem,will meet at the picnic area near Route 80.
還沒有理由覺得他們在追捕我們，所以冷靜
There's no reason to think they're onto us yet, so stay calm.
- 爸爸，我能和你說一會話麼？
- 現在不行。
- Dad, can I talk to you a minute?- Not now.
我想留下。
I was thinking about staying.
- 你不得去上課麼？
- 還有半個小時
- Don't you have school?- In half an hour.
我想留下。
I want to stay.
留下？
Stay?
你覺得現在是討論這個問題的時候麼
Do you think this is a good time to discuss this?
我們現在不能說。我們遇到麻煩了。
We can't talk now. We're in trouble here.
我告訴你了！
I taught you!
我告訴你了！我們不能打破我們之間的聯繫
I taught you! We cannot break rank.
一個集體的能力是由它最弱的一環決定的
A unit is only as good as its weakest link.
我們是一個集體！
We're a unit!
這些都是我教你的，不記得了麼？
I taught you all of this,don't you remember that?
我不想聽你
I don't want to hear you talking about this...
在你媽媽或者你弟弟面前說這些，聽見沒有？
in front of your mother or your brother, do you hear me?
我說，聽見沒有？
I said, do you hear me?
這回說完了沒？
Are we finished talking about this now?
泰勒女士
Mrs. Taylor.
把所有東西都拿出來，穿上袍子就行
Just remove everything and put on the gown.
幾分鐘內就可以見醫生了
The doctor will see you in a few minutes.
好的。我馬上就回來給你稱體重
All right. I'll be right back to weigh you.
能幫我拉拉鏈麼，親愛的？
Could you help me with this zipper, dear?
你知道昨晚伊利莎白·鮑威爾怎麼了麼？
Did you hear what happened to Elizabeth Powell last night?
不知道
No, I didn't.
聯邦調查局找她了
The FBl came to see her.
搶銀行，還殺死了警察的那次
The car that was used in that bank robbery...
他們用的車
where they killed those policemen...
是用她的信用卡租的
it was rented with her credit card.
你相信麼？
Can you believe it?
他們怎麼能拿到她的卡？她自己都從來不用。
How could they have got hold of her card? She never even uses it herself.
這就是為什麼她沒注意到卡不見了
That's how come she didn't notice it was gone.
那些人是一幫惡棍，泰勒女士
Those people are crooks, Mrs. Taylor.
他們很有可能就是從通訊錄裡查出她的電話
They probably just took her name out of the phone book...
然後假造了一張卡。
and made up a false card.
能想像這多背運麼？
Can you imagine the bad luck?
請找保羅·曼菲爾德先生。我是他妻子。
Paul Manfield, please. His wife.
我們很著急。
We're in a hurry.
格斯從我一個病人那偷了信用卡。他用它來租車。
Gus took plastic from one of my patients.He used it to rent the car.
真的？我要去抽根煙
Frankie? I'm going out for a smoke.
- 我們著急麼，媽媽？
- 嗯。我們得找到丹尼。
- Are we in a hurry, Mom?- Yeah. We have to get Danny.
希望你丈夫還好。
I hope your husband is all right.
好了，走吧
Okay, let's go.
- 媽媽，我在那見你
- 我們時間不多。
- Mom, I'll meet you there.- We don't have much time.
塞林格在《麥田里的守望者》中用意象……
Salinger uses imagery in Catcher in the Rye to-
- 抱歉。
- 怎麼？
- Excuse me.- Yes?
麥奎爾先生要見羅娜·菲利普斯
Mr. McGuire would like to see Lorna Phillips.
- 他寫假條了麼？
- 沒有，女士。
- Did he send a note?- No, ma'am.
菲利普斯小姐？
Ms. Phillips?
我們要走了。
We're leaving.
你沒和他們談？
You didn't ask them?
我談了。
I did.
阿瑟崩潰了。
Artie fell apart.
他根本不講理。
He didn't even make any sense.
沒有我們他活不下去。
Without us, he can't keep it going.
他需要我們支撐著他。
He needs us to hold him up.
所有家庭都會拆散的。
All families break up.
為什麼要把別人的人生當做自己的負擔？
Why do you have to carry the burden of someone else's life?
他是我父親
He's my father.
我愛你。
I love you.
但是我要離開了。
But I have to go.
我不知道怎麼道別。
I don't know how to say goodbye.
那就不要。
Well, don't.
- 他在哪？
- 他會來這。
- Where is he? - He'll be here.
他去和她女朋友道別了
He went to say goodbye to his girlfriend.
他比這知道得多
He knows better than this.
這裡是鮑勃·斯通，帶來Z-90新聞時間
This is Bob Stone, with a Z-90 newsbreak.
新澤西警方昨天下午報告了
New Jersey police have reported the death of Liberation Army member Gus Winant...
在搶劫銀行後一直在逃的自由軍成員格斯·維納特的死亡
at large after the bank robbery yesterday afternoon.
他在沃特福德附近偷了輛車並試圖逃逸，
He was shot resisting arrest near Waterford...
因拒捕而被槍擊。
where he had stolen a car,and was attempting to flee.
五點帶來更多，現在回到球賽。
More at 5:00.We return you now to the ball game.
把自行車從後面拿出來。
Get the bike out of the back.
騎上。
Now get on it.
你在說什麼，爸爸……
What are you talking about, Dad-
騎上車。你現在靠自己了，孩子
Get on the bike. You're on your own, kid.
我想讓你去朱利亞德
I want you to go to Juilliard.
但是爸爸，我想和你走
But, Dad, I want to go with you.
我們會再見的。你放心。
We'll see you again. You can be sure.
你媽媽和你外公都安排好了。
Your mother has arranged things with your grandfather.
給他打電話。
Call him.
你在這也有了些朋友了。
And I think you have some friends around here.
我愛你，寶貝兒
I love you, baby.
我們都愛你。
We all love you.
現在，去闖自己的人生吧
Now, go out there and make a difference.
你和我媽媽試過了。
Your mother and I tried.
不要讓任何人懷疑你。
Don't let anyone tell you any different.
再見，丹尼！
Goodbye, Danny!
English